So I'm back in the project and I want to implement these methods so that we can see how our application
Bu yzden projeye geri dndm ve uygulamann nasl davrandn grebilmek iin bu yntemleri
behaves.
uygulamak istiyorum.
And I only got one stateful component,
Ve yalnzca bir durum bileenim var.
the app.js file, this is nice but to really see how all the child components get re-rendered, I also want
Diablo Evet Kyle ho ama gerekten tm alt bileenlerin yeniden nasl oluturulduunu grmek iin bunlardan bazlarn durum
to turn some of them into stateful components so that we can implement these lifecycle methods because
bilgisi olan bileenler haline getirmek istiyorum, bylece bu yaam dngs yntemlerini uygulayabiliriz, nk bir yaam dngs
that's an important takeaway. If you need access to a lifecycle method,
yntemine erimeniz gerekirse bu nemli bir paket olabilir .
you need to have a stateful component.
Duruma dayal bir bileene sahip olmanz gerekir.
So a component created with class and by extending component,
Snfla ve bileenini genileterek ele almak iin bir bileen.
you can't do this for functional components.
Bunu ilevsel bileenler iin yapamazsnz.
So for the sake of this, I'll turn persons and person into stateful components, I will quickly do this
Bu yzden, bu alternatif hapishaneleri ve hapishaneyi durumsal bileenlere dntrmek iin abucak ikisini birden
for both and it's super easy to do. In the persons.js
yapardm ve cezaevinde yaplmas ok kolay.
file, we now no longer have a const persons,
Geen sonbaharda artk bir konserimiz yok artk.
we have a class and there the convention is to give this the component name but starting with a capital
Bir snfmz var ve oradaki szleme, hediye etmektir. Bileen ad ancak zaten
character already.
bir sermaye karakteriyle balyoruz.
Now this class should extend with the extends keyword component which you now need to import as a named
imdi bu snf extents anahtar szc bileeni ile geniletilmelidir; bu bileen, u andan itibaren yeniden ad bileeninden
import from react, component like this.
adlandrlm bir ie aktarma olarak ie aktarmanz gerekir.
Now a class then has a class body and in there, we will have this render method which we just saw on
imdi bir snfn snfsal bir yaps var ve daha sonra diyagramda grdmz ve
the diagram and which we also saw earlier. In there,
orada daha nce grdmz render yntemine sahibiz.
we now want to return some jsx, so our list
imdi, bazlar j olarak X listemize geri getirmek istiyoruz.
and as you learn props is not available here, we'll have this.props. So wherever you use props, it should
Ve pervane'nin bulunmadn rendiinizde burada bu pervaneye sahip olacaz. yleyse sahne kullandnz her yerde bu
be this.props now.
sahne olmaldr.
With that, I can remove the code down there and simply export Persons with a capital P, with that
imdi orada kodu kaldrabilir ve hzlca kurtardmz bir P harfine sahip kiileri kolayca da aktarabilir ve
let's quickly save this and let's see if our application still works,
uygulamann hala alp almadn grebiliriz.
Make sure npm start is still running,
NPM'nin almaya devam ettiinden emin olun.
and this looks good.
Ve bu iyi grnyor.
So now we turned our stateless component into a stateful component.
Dolaysyla, devletimizi daha az bileeni bir devletin tam bileeni haline getirdik.
Let's do the same for the person component, there
Ayn eyi, orada kii bileeni iin de yapalm.
we create a class, name it Person with a capital P, extend component which we then need to import as
Kendisinden bir sermaye P uzants bileenine sahip bir snf ad oluturuyoruz ki, ithal etmemiz gereken bir
a named import from react, define body for this class and add a render method to it.
isim olarak ithal etmemizi salyoruz, tepki snf olarak tanmlyoruz ve ona bir render yntemi katyoruz.
And in there, simply return the jsx like this and make sure to adjust the default
Ve sonra J'yi yalnzca bu gibi davranr ve varsaylan ayarladnzdan emin olun.
export to use a capital P and as before, props doesn't exist,
Propst yokken sermayenin P kullanmasn ve sormasn isteyin.
This should be this.props,
Bu, sahne parma olmaldr.
Now we adjusted this too
imdi de bunu ayarladk.
and here there are two more.
Ve burada iki tane daha var.
Now with that, that all props are exchanged, with that, let's implement lifecycle hooks in the next lecture.
imdi bununla birlikte tm sahne alverii, bir sonraki dersin iinde olduu gibi hayat yaamak iin izin veriliyor.